# 以往我们这些网友粉丝
People use to
# 这方便面都泡着吃
soak the instant noodles.
# 光泡不行 一定要煮一下
(You)can’t just soak them. (You)must boil them.
# 今天我给大家做一个炒方便面
Today, I will show you the stir-fried instant noodles.
# 这些料都可以下了
(You)can use these ingredients.
# 五彩炒方便面
The colourful stir-fried instant noodles.
# 二伯好 那边还一个呢
# 刚强 刚强这一乐我就特开心啊
# 好多网友粉丝说做点家常菜
Many fans want to see us making some home cooked dishes.
# 今天给大家你看到没有 方便面
Today, this recipe is for all of you. Instant noodles.
# 给大家炒一个方便面
(I am making) the stir-fried instant noodles.
# 以往我们这些网友粉丝
Our fans use to
# 还有小白同志们
# 这方便面都泡着吃
consume soaked instant noodles.
# 但是泡的他们泡的也
Even with soaking (method), some of them
# 有的泡的方法也不对
didn’t do it correctly.
# 光泡不行 一定要煮一下
(You) can’t just soak them. (You) must simmer them.
# 主要这方便面这个聚绺伸开了
Mainly to spread out the noodles.
# 一是便于消化
One is for easy digestion.
# 另外吃起来比较舒服
Another is for better taste.
# 其实这方便面有很多吃法
Actually, there are many ways of cooking instant noodles.
# 煮的时候一定要煮两遍
(You)must boil them twice.
# 第一遍水不要
Drain away the first batch of water.
# 第二遍水再调味
Season the second batch.
# 这是煮方便面
This is boiling method.
# 但是咱们把这方便面
But today we
# 让网友有更多的吃法
will show the fans another way.
# 今天我给大家做一个炒方便面
Today, I will make the stir-fried instant noodles.
# 这个烹调方法是一个软炒的方法
This recipe uses a gentle frying technique.
# 软炒二伯知道
Er Bai knew this.
# 在酒店这里边要搁一点毛汤
Hotel chefs use Maotang.
# 就是用骨头煮的汤
(Maotang) is the stock made from bones.
# 这里边我们要搁点盐搁点底味
We add bit of salt as the base flavour.
# 因为这面不管是伊面
Whether using Yimen
# 还是我们其他面条 它没有底味
or other noodles, they don’t have base flavour.
# 给它搁点盐 少搁点油
Adding bit of salt, less bit of oil.
# 它煮完这个面
Once the noodles are done.
# 不管是手工面或者是方便面
Whether handmade noodles or instant noodles,
# 它不容易粘连
They won’t stick together.
# 一会你看这面 它有一个过程
Watch the noodles.
# 加热以后它慢慢开始回软
Gradually and slowly, they become soft after
# 煮的时间大约在一分多钟
simmering about a minute.
# 它就开始变软了 就松散了
They become loose when they are soft.
# 但是它这腰还伸不开
But they are not fully expanded yet.
# 一定要把这面煮伸开腰
Make sure the noodles are fully expaned.
# 小火咱煮着
Use gentle heat.
# 如果煮着吃的话再进行二遍煮
Change the boiling water and simmer them again if you like them simmered.
# 煮出来这面特别软
The noodles are super soft.
# 吃起来口感特别好
Super tasty.
# 在这煮面当中咱们就开始配些小料
Let’s prepare other ingredients whilst under simmering.
# 豆芽是绿豆芽
(They are) green bean sprouts.
# 韭菜或者韭黄 蒜黄都可以
Chinese chives or similar are fine.
# 不宜太多
Not too much.
# 韭菜多了蒜黄多了就不香了
It won’t taste nice if too much chives.
# 就一点点是最好
Best just to put a little.
# 豆芽白的 韭菜绿的
White bean sprouts and green chives.
# 这胡萝卜丝别切太粗
Carrots need to be finely shredded.
# 基本跟面的比例 粗细差不多就行
Similar thickness to a noodle.
# 这个主要是一个增色
Mainly to add some colour.
# 另外增加原料的营养
And more nutritious.
# 你看这面都伸开腰了
Watch the noodles are expanded.
# 咱们还得给它留点余地
We don’t want them fully expanded.
# 待会还要炒
Still need to fry them later.
# 接着切 洋葱丝
Onion, finely sliced.
# 木耳涨发完了以后拿水煮它一下
Briefly simmer the black fungus after soaking.
# 切成丝
Shred them finely.
# 也可以用香菇 俩鸡蛋
Can also use shiitake mushroom. Two eggs.
# 还得搁点肉丝呢吧 大爷
Da Ye, put some shredded pork in?
# 不要 咱们要来个素一点的
No, we go vegetarian.
# 因为是家常菜 就简单一点
Make it simple because it is home cooking.
# 他们家还有瑶柱呢大爷
# 谁家呀 老饭骨的家
# 好了 开火
All done. Turn on the heat.
# 大爷今选的又经济又实惠
Cheap and cheerful choices from Da Ye.
# 还好吃啊
And tasty!
# 大爷比我会选菜
Da Ye knows how to pick and choose fresh vegetables.
# 这料(葱花)不用太多
Don’t need much scallions.
# 咱们第一步先炒鸡蛋
First, we fry some eggs.
# 来点油
Bit of oil.
# 油多了 回来点
Too much oil. Scoop some back.
# 你看我在家里头我一般的都是
At home, I normally
# 它那料包我不用
don’t use that seasoning pack.
# 我就单调
I make my own.
# 单调有时候我会炒一个两个鸡蛋
When I make my own seasoning, I use one or two eggs.
# 拿那个鸡蛋做汤底
I use the eggs for the soup base.
# 它出来以后那个汤
# 不用它那料包直接我们
We get umami taste from the eggs
# 用鸡蛋的鲜味
instead of seasoning pack.
# 炒菜也有技巧 为什么先炒鸡蛋
Also need some techniques in stir frying. Why fry the eggs first?
# 省的刷一回锅
Saving to clean the wok.
# 再来点底油
Some oil.
# 一会把这面给我拿来
Bring me the noodles later.
# 酱油
Soy sauce.
# 老抽 再来点 我怕黑了
Dark soy sauce. More. I worried it will be too dark.
# 还有料呢 黑不了
It won’t. Still have other ingredients.
# 这些料都可以下了
Put the rest in.
# 再来点黄酒
Add some Huangjiu.
# 顺着锅边
From the side of the wok.
# 酱油
Soy sauce
# 五颜六色
Colourful
# 酱油和老抽下去以后
After soy sauce and dark soy sauce,
# 颜色够了不用太搁更多的盐了
It is dark enough. No need for more salt.
# 少来一点糖
Less bit of sugar.
# 家里有老人不能吃的也可以不搁
Don’t need sugar if there are elders in the family.
# 胡椒粉
Ground white pepper
# 它这颜色要给它炒匀
Mix the colour well.
# 菜呢 因为这些菜
These vegetables,
# 除了韭菜怕炒 可以有时候后放
put Chinese chives in later because they are cooked very quickly.
# 其他都是可以多在锅里多炒一会
Other vegetables can be stir fried for a longer time.
# 你像葱头 胡萝卜多炒一会不要紧
Like onions, carrots.
# 有点回软了 全软了
All soft now.
# 把鸡蛋放下去
Add the eggs.
# 你看这面开始伸腰了
The noodles are expanding now.
# OK了 OK
# 香油要吗大爷 来一点
Da Ye, do you need some sesame oil? A little.
# 来一点香油 香油才香呢
Pour little. Sesame oil smells nice.
# 二伯给盛一下
Er Bai, please dish it up.
# 就扒 扒的快
# 盛的是真有水平
# 要摆的跟山一样
# 谢谢二伯 谢什么呀 谢谢
Thank you, Er Bai.
# 二伯这人高马大力量大
# 手劲大
# 五彩炒方便面 走起
# 我们网友粉丝们在家懒得做饭
# 其实就这么一个方便面
# 炒好了 五颜六色的
# 又营养又健康 又经济又实惠
# 今天做这个有两个提示
# 一个提示就是
# 我们好多网友粉丝小饭骨们
Many our fans
# 平时可能都是拿那个
may buy those
# 买那个碗的或者袋的 都是泡面
instant noodles in a bag or bowl package.
# 有时候工作劳累一天了 到家呢
Sometimes, they are tired after a long day at work.
# 水也不是很热 泡泡就吃了
Sometimes, the water is not hot enough. They still manage to eat it.
# 这种方法是不对的
This way is wrong.
# 方便面好多人也在说方便面不健康
Many people also say that instant noodles are unhealthy.
# 这也不让大家多吃
We suggest that people have less of them.
# 所以我建议大家也引导大家
So, I suggest that people spread words to others.
# 方便面在吃的时候泡两遍
Soak instant noodles twice before consumption.
# 或者煮一遍
Or simmer them.
# 中间最好换换水
Change boiling water once during cooking.
# 炒方面这个类型是属于
This type of frying is called
# 一个在烹调方法里边呈现的是软炒
tender (stir) frying.
# 这呈现在哪呢
Where was it originated?
# 在广东菜里边有一个炒伊面
There is a stir fry Yimen dish in the Cantonese cuisine.
# 面条是经过擀 煮然后油炸
It uses handmade noodles, simmering then deep frying.
# 然后搁这存着
After that, the noodles are kept
# 一旦来事了来买卖了
and ready to cook with orders.
# 把油炸的伊面下锅
Simmer the deep fried Yimen in the wok
# 弄点肉汤 毛汤
with some meat stock.
# 让它回软加上一些料头
Make noodles soft again with other ingredients.
# 它是属于叫软炒法
This is called tender frying method.